

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Web Development (Full-Time) Masai School | Bangalore July 2022 - May 2023

B-Tech in Mechanical Engineering Dr. B.C. Roy Eng. College, Durgapur August 2016 - July 2020

Intermediate

Bharat Sen. Sc.School, Kota, Rajasthan March 2014 - May 2016

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript
- Chakra UI
- HTML
- GitHub
- CSS
- Next.js
- DSA
- Node.js
- React
- Express
- Redux
- Mongo DB
- Typescript
- Mongoose

SOFT SKILLS

- Adaptability
- Team Collaboration
- Problem-solving
- Consistency

LANGUAGES KNOWN:

- English (S,R,W)
- Hindi (S,RW)
- Bengali(S)

CERTIFICATIONS

Vocational Training

Mejia Thermal Power Plant | D.V.C July 2019

Vocational Training on CATIA

Indo Danish Tool Room | Jamshedpur January 2018

V.T on CNC Milling

Indo Danish Tool Room | Jamshedpur January 2018

RISHAV CHAKRABORTY

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

□ chakrabortyrishav048@gmail.com

() +919123160776

in linkedin/Rishav Chakraborty

github/Rishav Chakraborty

rishav048.github.io

Bokaro steel city, Jharkhand

PROFILE SNAPSHOT

A self-motivated, hard-working, and ambitious Full-Stack Web Developer and a good learner with proficiency in JavaScript. Having a Problem-solving mindset, and 1200+ hrs of hands-on experience in developing fully functional E-commerce applications. Looking forward to working as a developer and competent employee in an exciting tech company.

PROJECTS

Clone: Nykaa.com 🔘

An e-commerce website to purchase beauty products.

Features:

- Sign-in/Sign-up.
- Landing Page, Carousel & Products Page
- Real-time product filter option & Pagination.
- Users can set products per page.
- Add to cart and remove functionality.

Tech Stack: React | HTML | CSS | Chakra UI | Bootstrap

An individual project built in the span of 6 days.

Clone: Advanceautoparts.com

Advance Auto Parts an American automotive aftermarket parts provider.

Features:

- Sign-in/Sign-up.
- User authentication using Node.js
- Landing Page, Products Page, Cart Page, Payment Page.
- Sort & filter functionality along with pagination.
- Add to cart and remove functionality.
- Payment Gateway.

Areas of responsibility:

- Built the website's Admin Side.
- Included sort& filter functionality.
- Create/Read/Update/Delete (CRUD) operations on the database.
- Created the dashboard to show the products per category.
- Implemented Search functionality.

Tech Stack: React| Redux | Chakra UI | NodeJS | Express | MongoDB

A collaborative project built by a team of 5, executed in 6 days.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Business Research Analyst

Markable Solutions | April 2021 - April 2022

- Used Excel functions to organize and analyze data.
- Created charts, graphs, and presentations for leadership teams.
- Developed recommendations to improve business operations going forward.
- Identified trends and make recommendations for improvements.

Sales Engineer

Minimac Systems Pvt Ltd | August 2020 - April 2021

- Responsible for interacting with the clients and solving their queries.
- Maintained the records of customer interactions and follow up with the clients.
- Conveyed customer technical requirements to the Internal Engineering teams.
- Demonstrated products, services, and solutions to potential clients.
- Identifyied the customer's current and future requirements.